Finding Aid for Provost (University of Michigan) records, 1934-1951
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Provost (University of Michigan) records 1934-1951
University of Michigan. Provost.
87272 Bimu B6 2
Administrative files of provosts E. Blythe Stason and James P. Adams relating to annual budget, staffing, liaison with the Board of Regents, and the relationship of the University to the state, alumni, private foundations and the general public.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
15 linear feet
Records were received through donors 2492 and 4328.
No further additions to the records are expected.
The records are open to research without restriction.
During the first years of the Presidency of Alexander G. Ruthven, the University of Michigan underwent a remarkable growth. To help with his many responsibilities, Ruthven instituted a system of Vice-Presidents, each of whom was responsible for a given area within the University. Even with these administrative officers, however, the President was burdened with matters of budgeting, state relations, staffing, planning, and problems of the individual schools, colleges, libraries, and other units that reported directly to the President's Office. To meet this need, the Board of Regents, in April 1938, created the position of Provost of the University "to aid the President by performing such of the President's functions as shall from time to time be delegated by him or by the Board of Regents." E. Blythe Stason of the University Law School, who had already been performing many of these functions, was appointed first Provost.
In January 1945, James P. Adams replaced Stason as Provost. That same month, the Regents amended the by-laws making the Provost the chief executive of the University next to the President. During his nearly seven years as Provost, Adams came to discharge many of the executive duties formerly within the province of the President. On many matters, he corresponded directly with members of the Board of Regents. He also took the initiative on matters of faculty salaries, the appointment of administrative personnel, the preparation of the budget, and the enlargement of the teaching staff.
Many on campus felt that Adams was being groomed to replace Ruthven as President. He was an efficient administrator and was well liked by members of the academic community. Adams, however, preferred to move back East. He removed his name from consideration as a successor to Ruthven, and retired on July 1, 1951. There was no attempt to replace Adams. Instead the duties of the Provost were split up among various University Vice Presidents.
Summary Contents List
Topical Files, 1934-1944 -- Box 1-2
World War II university programs --Box 3
Financial records, 1941-1945 -- Box 3-4
Miscellaneous topical files -- Box 4
Special Service Personnel -- Box 4-5
Counseling Project -- Box 5
Topical Files
1945-1946 -- Box 5-7
1946-1947 -- Box 7-9
1947-1948 -- Box 8-10
1948-1949 -- Box 10-11
1949-1950 -- Box 11-13
1950-1951 -- Box 13-15
John A. Perkins (assistant provost) files -- Box 15
Administrative files of provosts E. Blythe Stason and James P. Adams relating to annual budget, staffing, liaison with the Board of Regents, and the relationship of the University to the state, alumni, private foundations and the general public.
Subjects:
University of Michigan--Administration.; University of Michigan--Alumni and alumnae.; University of Michigan. Board of Regents.; University of Michigan--Finance.; University of Michigan. Provost.
Contributors:
Adams, James P. (James Pickwell), 1895-1969.; Stason, E. Blythe (Edwin Blythe), 1891-1972.
- Topical Files
  - 1934-1944
    - A (miscellaneous) (Box 1)
    - Advisory Board on University Policies (Box 1)
    - Alumni Association (Box 1)
    - American (Box 1)
    - B (miscellaneous) (Box 1)
    - Business Administration, School of (Box 1)
    - C (miscellaneous) (Box 1)
    - Criminology, Bureau of (Box 1)
    - D (miscellaneous) (Box 1)
    - Detroit Engineering Society (Box 1)
    - Dormitory gifts to university (Box 1)
    - E (miscellaneous) (Box 1)
    - Encyclopedia contributions (Box 1)
    - F (miscellaneous) (Box 1)
    - Faculty Evaluation, Regent's Committee on Educational Policies (Box 1)
    - Faculty Personnel Committee
      - 1942-1943 (Box 1)
      - 1943-1944 (Box 1)
      - 1944-1945 (Box 1)
    - Faculty Relations with State Government (Box 1)
    - Fees (Committee on University) (Box 1)
    - Financial literature (Box 1)
    - G (miscellaneous) (Box 1)
    - Government Bureau of (Box 1)
    - H (miscellaneous) (Box 1)
    - Hatch Act (Box 1)
    - Health Service (Box 1)
    - Herbert, J. Joseph (Box 1)
    - I (miscellaneous) (Box 1)
    - J (miscellaneous) (Box 1)
    - Japanese American students (Box 1)
    - K (miscellaneous) (Box 1)
    - L (miscellaneous) (Box 1)
    - Legislature, 1934-1937 (Box 1)
    - Legislature, 1939-1942 (Box 2)
    - Legislature, 1943 (Box 2)
    - M (miscellaneous) (Box 2)
    - Michigan Child Guidance Institute (Box 2)
    - Michigan Daily (Box 2)
    - N (miscellaneous) (Box 2)
    - Neuropsychiatric Institute (Box 2)
    - O (miscellaneous) (Box 2)
    - P (miscellaneous) (Box 2)
    - Personnel (married women, sick leaves, and vacation allowances) (Box 2)
    - Postwar plans (Box 2)
    - Proposals for state supervisory board for institutions of higher learning (Box 2)
    - Psychopathic Hospital (Box 2)
    - Public and Social Administration, Institute of (Box 2)
    - Q-R (miscellaneous) (Box 2)
    - Regents (Box 2)
    - Residence Halls, 1939-1944, 2 folders (Box 2)
    - Residence Halls (director's reports), 1939-1941 (Box 2)
    - Residence Halls in other schools (Box 2)
    - Ruthven, Alexander (Box 2)
    - S (miscellaneous) (Box 2)
    - Salaries and wages (Box 2)
    - Sloan Foundation (Box 2)
    - Smith, Ira (Box 2)
    - Smith, Shirley W (Box 2)
    - Statistics (Box 2)
    - Subversive activities (Box 2)
    - T (miscellaneous) (Box 2)
    - U (miscellaneous) (Box 2)
    - V (miscellaneous) (Box 2)
    - W (miscellaneous) (Box 2)
    - War Leaves (Box 2)
    - XYZ (miscellaneous) (Box 2)
  - 1945-1946
    - A (miscellaneous) (Box 5)
    - Admissions (Box 5)
    - Architecture and Design, College of (Box 5)
    - Army (Box 5)
    - Art and archaeology (Box 5)
    - B (miscellaneous) (Box 5)
    - Briggs, Robert (Box 6)
    - Budget (to July 1, 1946) (Box 6)
    - Budget Administration, Committee on (Box 6)
    - Business Administration, School of (Box 6)
    - C (miscellaneous) (Box 6)
    - D (miscellaneous) (Box 6)
    - Dahlstrom-Wengen case (Box 6)
    - Dentistry, School of (Box 6)
    - E (miscellaneous) (Box 6)
    - Economic Status of Faculty (Box 6)
    - Education, School of (Box 6)
    - Educational Investigations (Box 6)
    - Engineering College (Box 6)
    - Extension Service (Box 6)
    - F (miscellaneous) (Box 6)
    - Fairbanks, Avard (Box 6)
    - Foreign students (Box 6)
    - Forestry, School of (Box 6)
    - G (miscellaneous) (Box 6)
    - Graduate School (Box 6)
    - Graduate School (dean) (Box 6)
    - H (miscellaneous) (Box 6)
    - Hospital (Box 6)
    - I-J (miscellaneous) (Box 6)
    - K (miscellaneous) (Box 6)
    - L (miscellaneous) (Box 6)
    - Law School (Box 6)
    - Legislature 1945 (Box 6)
    - Literary College (Box 6)
    - Literary College (needs) (Box 6)
    - M (miscellaneous) (Box 6)
    - Medical School (Box 6)
    - Museums (Box 6)
    - Music, School of (Box 6)
    - N (miscellaneous) (Box 6)
    - Navy (Box 6)
    - Nursing, School of (Box 6)
    - O (miscellaneous) (Box 6)
    - P (miscellaneous) (Box 6)
    - Perkins, John A. (assistant provost) (Box 7)
      - [A-H] (Box 7)
      - [I-Q] (Box 7)
      - [R-Z] (Box 7)
    - Pharmacy, College of (Box 7)
    - Public Administration, Institute of (Box 7)
    - Public Health, School of (Box 7)
    - R (miscellaneous) (Box 7)
    - Regents (Box 7)
    - Reorganization (Box 7)
    - Ruthven, Alexander (Box 7)
    - Sa-Sn (miscellaneous) (Box 7)
    - So-Sz (miscellaneous) (Box 7)
    - Student Religious Association (Box 7)
    - T (miscellaneous) (Box 7)
    - Tibbitts, Clark (Box 7)
    - U-V (miscellaneous) (Box 7)
    - Veterans (Box 7)
    - W (miscellaneous) (Box 7)
    - Williams, Robert (Box 7)
    - Women, Dean of (Box 7)
    - XYZ (miscellaneous) (Box 7)
  - 1946-1947
    - A (miscellaneous) (Box 7)
    - Admissions (Box 7)
    - Applications for Grants (Box 7)
    - Architecture and Design, College of (Box 7)
    - Army (Box 7)
    - Art, Museum of (Box 7)
    - B (miscellaneous) (Box 7)
    - Briggs, Robert P (Box 7)
    - Budget 1945-1946 (Box 7)
    - Budget 1946-1947 (Box 7)
    - Budget Administration, Committee on
      - General (Box 7)
      - Minutes (Box 7)
    - Business Administration, School of (Box 7)
    - Bylaws (Box 7)
    - C (miscellaneous) (Box 7)
    - Cooperation with Educational Institutions (Box 7)
    - D (miscellaneous) (Box 7)
    - Deans (communications with) (Box 7)
    - Dentistry, School of (Box 7)
    - E (miscellaneous) (Box 7)
    - Education, School of (Box 7)
    - Elliott, Eugene B (Box 7)
    - Engagements accepted (Box 7)
    - Engineering College (Box 7)
    - Extension Service (Box 7)
    - F (miscellaneous) (Box 8)
    - Foreign students (Box 8)
    - Forestry and Conservation, School of (Box 8)
    - G (miscellaneous) (Box 8)
    - Government students (Box 8)
    - Graduate School (Box 8)
    - H (miscellaneous) (Box 8)
    - Hospital (Box 8)
    - Housing (Box 8)
    - Human Adjustment, Institute for (Box 8)
    - I (miscellaneous) (Box 8)
    - J (miscellaneous) (Box 8)
    - K (miscellaneous) (Box 8)
    - L (miscellaneous) (Box 8)
    - Law School (Box 8)
    - Legislature (Box 8)
    - Library (Box 8)
    - Literary College (Box 8)
    - M (miscellaneous) (Box 8)
    - Medical School (Box 8)
    - Museums (Box 8)
    - Music, School of (Box 8)
    - N (miscellaneous) (Box 8)
    - Navy (Box 8)
    - Niehuss, Marvin (Box 8)
    - Nursing, School of (Box 8)
    - O (miscellaneous) (Box 8)
    - P (miscellaneous) (Box 8)
    - Pharmacy, College of (Box 8)
    - Physical Education (Box 8)
    - Plant Extension (Box 8)
    - Public Health, School of (Box 8)
    - Q-R (miscellaneous) (Box 8)
    - Questionnaires (Box 8)
    - Regents (Box 8)
    - Ruthven, Alexander G (Box 8)
    - S (miscellaneous) (Box 8)
    - Students, Dean of (Box 8)
    - Student Religious Association (Box 8)
    - Summer Session (Box 8)
    - Survey Research Center (Box 8)
    - T (miscellaneous) (Box 8)
    - University Policies, Statement (Box 9)
    - Veterans (Box 9)
    - W (miscellaneous) (Box 9)
    - Watkins, Herbert (Box 9)
    - Williams, Robert, L (Box 9)
    - Women, Dean of (Box 9)
  - 1947-1948
    - A (miscellaneous) (Box 9)
    - Admissions (Box 9)
    - Applications for Grants (Box 9)
    - Army (Box 9)
    - Architecture and Design, College of (Box 9)
    - Association of Governing Boards (Ann Arbor meeting) (Box 9)
    - B (miscellaneous) (Box 9)
    - Briggs, Robert P (Box 9)
    - Budget 1947-1948 (Box 9)
    - Budget Administration, Committee on (Box 9)
    - Business Administration, School of (Box 9)
    - C (miscellaneous) (Box 9)
    - Clements Library (Box 9)
    - Cooley Memorial (Box 9)
    - Cooperation with Educational Institutions (Box 9)
    - D (miscellaneous) (Box 9)
    - Dentistry, School of (Box 9)
    - Divisions (Box 9)
    - E (miscellaneous) (Box 9)
    - Education, School of (Box 9)
    - Elliott, Eugene B (State Superintendent of Public Instruction) (Box 9)
    - Engagements accepted (Box 9)
    - Engineering College (Box 9)
    - Extension Service (Box 9)
    - F (miscellaneous) (Box 9)
    - Fees, Committee on University (Box 9)
    - Foreign students (Box 9)
    - Forestry and Conservation, School of (Box 9)
    - G (miscellaneous) (Box 9)
    - Government studies (Box 9)
    - Graduate School (Box 9)
    - H (miscellaneous) (Box 9)
    - Hospital (Box 9)
    - Human Adjustment (Box 9)
    - I-J (miscellaneous) (Box 9)
    - K (miscellaneous) (Box 9)
    - L (miscellaneous) (Box 9)
    - Law School (Box 9)
    - Legislature (Box 9)
    - Library (Box 9)
    - Literary College (Box 9)
    - M (miscellaneous) (Box 9)
    - Medical School (Box 9)
    - Museums (Box 9)
    - Music, School of (Box 9)
    - N (miscellaneous) (Box 10)
    - Navy (Box 10)
    - Niehuss, Marvin L (Box 10)
    - Nursing (Box 10)
    - P (miscellaneous) (Box 10)
    - Pharmacy (Box 10)
    - Physical Education (Box 10)
    - Public Health (Box 10)
    - Q-R (miscellaneous) (Box 10)
    - Questionnaires (Box 10)
    - Regents (Box 10)
    - Ruthven, Alexander G (Box 10)
    - S (miscellaneous) (Box 10)
    - Student Religious Association (Box 10)
    - Students, Dean of (Box 10)
    - Summer Session (Box 10)
    - Survey Research Center (Box 10)
    - T (miscellaneous) (Box 10)
    - University Senate (Box 10)
    - V (miscellaneous) (Box 10)
    - W (miscellaneous) (Box 10)
    - Watkins, Herbert G (Box 10)
    - Williams, R.L. (Box 10)
    - Women, Dean of (Box 10)
    - XYZ (miscellaneous) (Box 10)
  - 1948-1949
    - A (miscellaneous) (Box 10)
    - Admissions (Box 10)
    - Applications for Grants (Box 10)
    - Architecture and Design (Box 10)
    - Army (Box 10)
    - B (miscellaneous) (Box 10)
    - Biological Sciences, Division of (Box 10)
    - Briggs, R.P. (Box 10)
    - Budget for 1948-1949 (Box 10)
    - Budget Administration, Committee on (Box 10)
    - Bureau of School Services (Box 10)
    - Business Administration (Box 10)
    - C (miscellaneous) (Box 10)
    - Clements Library (Box 10)
    - D (miscellaneous) (Box 10)
    - Dentistry (Box 10)
    - E (miscellaneous) (Box 10)
    - Education (Box 10)
    - Engagements accepted (Box 10)
    - Engineering (Box 10)
    - Engineering Research Institute (including Aeronautical Research Center) (Box 10)
    - Extension Service (Box 10)
    - F (miscellaneous) (Box 10)
    - Fine Arts, Division of (Box 10)
    - Foreign Students (Box 10)
    - Forestry and Conservation (Box 10)
    - G (miscellaneous) (Box 10)
    - Government Students (Box 10)
    - Graduate School (Box 10)
    - H (miscellaneous) (Box 10)
    - Health Sciences, Division of (Box 10)
    - Hospital Correspondence (Box 10)
    - Human Adjustment, Institute for (Box 10)
    - I (miscellaneous) (Box 11)
    - Institute for Social Research (Survey Research Center) (Box 11)
    - J (miscellaneous) (Box 11)
    - K (miscellaneous) (Box 11)
    - L (miscellaneous) (Box 11)
    - Lane Hall (Box 11)
    - Law (Box 11)
    - Legislature (Box 11)
    - Library (Box 11)
    - Literature, Science and the Arts (Box 11)
    - M (miscellaneous) (Box 11)
    - Medical School (Box 11)
    - Museums (Box 11)
    - Music (Box 11)
    - N (miscellaneous) (Box 11)
    - Navy (Box 11)
    - Niehuss, Marvin L. (Box 11)
    - Northwood, Lawrence K. (Box 11)
    - Nursing (Box 11)
    - O (miscellaneous) (Box 11)
    - P (miscellaneous) (Box 11)
    - Perkins, John A (Box 11)
    - Pharmacy (Box 11)
    - Phoenix Project (Box 11)
    - Physical Education (Box 11)
    - Public Health (Box 11)
    - Public Instruction, Superintendent of (Box 11)
    - Q-R (miscellaneous) (Box 11)
    - Questionnaires (Box 11)
    - Regents (Box 11)
    - Rockefeller Center (Box 11)
    - S (miscellaneous) (Box 11)
    - Senate (Box 11)
    - Social Work, Institute of (Box 11)
    - Students, Dean of (Box 11)
    - Summer Session (Box 11)
    - T (miscellaneous) (Box 11)
    - Thurber, Richard M. (Box 11)
    - U (miscellaneous) (Box 11)
    - V (miscellaneous) (Box 11)
    - Veterans' Hospital (Box 11)
    - W (miscellaneous) (Box 11)
    - Women, Dean of (Box 11)
    - XYZ (miscellaneous) (Box 11)
  - 1949-1950
    - A (miscellaneous) (Box 11)
    - Admissions (Box 11)
    - Applications for Grants (Box 11)
    - Architecture and Design (Box 11)
    - Army (Box 11)
    - B (miscellaneous) (Box 11)
    - Biological Sciences, Division of (Box 11)
    - Biological Station (Box 11)
    - Briggs, R.P. (Box 12)
    - Budget 1949-1950 (Box 12)
    - Bureau of School Services (Box 12)
    - Business Administration (Box 12)
    - C (miscellaneous) (Box 12)
    - Clements Library (Box 12)
    - D (miscellaneous) (Box 12)
    - Dentistry (Box 12)
    - Distinguished Professorship (Box 12)
    - E (miscellaneous) (Box 12)
    - Education (Box 12)
    - Engagements accepted (Box 12)
    - Engineering (Box 12)
    - Engineering Research Institute (Box 12)
    - Extension Service (Box 12)
    - F (miscellaneous) (Box 12)
    - Faculty Research Fellowships (Box 12)
    - Fees (Box 12)
    - Foreign Students (Box 12)
    - Forestry and Conservation, School of (Box 12)
    - G (miscellaneous) (Box 12)
    - Government Students (Box 12)
    - Graduate School (Box 12)
    - H (miscellaneous) (Box 12)
    - Hospital Miscellaneous (Box 12)
    - Human Adjustment, Institute for (Box 12)
    - I (miscellaneous) (Box 12)
    - J (miscellaneous) (Box 12)
    - K (miscellaneous) (Box 12)
    - L (miscellaneous) (Box 12)
    - Lane Hall (Box 12)
    - Law (Box 12)
    - Legislature (Box 12)
    - Library (Box 12)
    - Literature, Science and the Arts (Box 12)
    - M (miscellaneous) (Box 12)
    - Medical School (Box 12)
    - Museums (Box 12)
    - Music (Box 12)
    - N (miscellaneous) (Box 12)
    - Navy (Box 12)
    - Niehuss, Marvin L. (Box 12)
    - Nursing (Box 12)
    - O (miscellaneous) (Box 12)
    - P (miscellaneous) (Box 12)
    - Perkins, John A. (Box 12)
    - Pharmacy (Box 12)
    - Phoenix Project (Box 12)
    - Physical Education (Box 12)
    - Plant Extension (Box 12)
    - Public Health (Box 12)
    - Public Instruction, Department of (Box 12)
    - Q-R (miscellaneous) (Box 13)
    - Questionnaires (Box 13)
    - Regents (Box 13)
    - Ruthven, Alexander G. (Box 13)
    - S (miscellaneous) (Box 13)
    - Senate (Box 13)
    - Social Research, Institute for (Box 13)
    - Social Work, Institute of (Box 13)
    - Students, Dean of (Box 13)
    - Summer Session (Box 13)
    - T (miscellaneous) (Box 13)
    - U (miscellaneous) (Box 13)
    - V (miscellaneous) (Box 13)
    - W (miscellaneous) (Box 13)
    - Watkins, Herbert G. (Box 13)
    - Williams, R.L., 2 folders (Box 13)
    - Women, Dean of (Box 13)
    - XYZ (miscellaneous) (Box 13)
  - 1950-1951
    - A (miscellaneous) (Box 13)
    - Accrediting (Box 13)
    - Admissions (Box 13)
    - Applications for Grants (Box 13)
    - Architecture and Design (Box 13)
    - Army (Box 13)
    - B (miscellaneous) (Box 13)
    - Biological Sciences, Divisions of (Box 13)
    - Briggs, R.P. / Pierpont, W.K. (Box 13)
    - Budget 1950-1951 (Box 13)
    - Budget Administration, Committee on (Box 13)
    - Bureau of School Services (Box 13)
    - Business Administration (Box 13)
    - By-laws (Box 13)
    - C (miscellaneous) (Box 13)
    - Clements Library (Box 13)
    - Copilowish (Copi),Irving M. (Box 13)
    - D (miscellaneous) (Box 13)
    - Deans (Communications to) (Box 13)
    - Dentistry (Box 13)
    - E (miscellaneous) (Box 13)
    - Education (Box 13)
    - Engagements accepted (Box 14)
    - Engineering (Box 14)
    - Engineering College Deanship (Box 14)
    - Engineering Research Institute (Box 14)
    - Extension Service (Box 14)
    - F (miscellaneous) (Box 14)
    - Fees (Box 14)
    - Fire Inspection (Box 14)
    - Ford Foundation Grant (Box 14)
    - Foreign Students (Box 14)
    - Forestry and Conservation (Box 14)
    - G (miscellaneous) (Box 14)
    - Graduate School (Box 14)
    - H (miscellaneous) (Box 14)
    - Health Service (Box 14)
    - Hospital (miscellaneous) (Box 14)
    - Human Adjustment, Institute for (Box 14)
    - I (miscellaneous) (Box 14)
    - J (miscellaneous) (Box 14)
    - K (miscellaneous) (Box 14)
    - L (miscellaneous) (Box 14)
    - Lane Hall (Box 14)
    - Law (Box 14)
    - Legislature (Box 14)
    - Library (Box 14)
    - Literature, Science and the Arts (Box 14)
    - M (miscellaneous) (Box 14)
    - Medical School (Box 14)
    - Military Status of Faculty Members (Box 14)
    - Museums (Box 14)
    - Music (Box 14)
    - N (miscellaneous) (Box 14)
    - National Defense (Box 14)
    - Navy (Box 14)
    - News Service (Box 14)
    - Niehuss, Marvin L. (Box 14)
    - Nursing (Box 14)
    - O (miscellaneous) (Box 14)
    - P (miscellaneous) (Box 14)
    - Perkins, John A. (Box 14)
    - Pharmacy (Box 14)
    - Pharmacy Deanship, College of (Box 15)
    - Phoenix Project (Box 15)
    - Physical Education (Box 15)
    - Plant Extension (Box 15)
    - Presidents Report, 1949-1950 (Box 15)
    - Programs (Box 15)
    - Public Health (Box 15)
    - Public Instruction, Department of (Box 15)
    - Q-R (miscellaneous) (Box 15)
    - Questionnaires (Box 15)
    - Regents (Box 15)
    - S (miscellaneous) (Box 15)
    - Senate (Box 15)
    - Social Research, Institute of (Box 15)
    - Social Sciences, Division of the (Box 15)
    - Social Work, Institute of (Box 15)
    - Social Work Deanship (Perkins file) (Box 15)
    - Social Work Deanship, School of (Box 15)
    - Statistics (Box 15)
    - Students, Dean of (Box 15)
    - Sumner Session (Box 15)
    - T (miscellaneous) (Box 15)
    - U (miscellaneous) (Box 15)
    - V (miscellaneous) (Box 15)
    - W (miscellaneous) (Box 15)
    - Watkins, Herbert G. (Box 15)
    - Women, Dean of (Box 15)
    - Women, Dean of (appointment of) [2 folders] (Box 15)
- World War II University Programs, 1943-1945
  - Army Air Force (Box 3)
  - Army and Navy Programs (Box 3)
  - Army Specialized Training Program (Box 3)
  - Civil Affairs Training School (Box 3)
  - Curtiss-Wright Corporation (Box 3)
  - Deferment of Students (Box 3)
  - Division for Emergency Training (Box 3)
  - Epidemiology (Box 3)
  - Engineering, Science and Management War Training (Box 3)
  - Japanese Language School (Box 3)
  - Judge Advocate General's School (Box 3)
  - Latin American Studies for Army Officers (Box 3)
  - Manpower Commission (Box 3)
  - Meteorological School (Box 3)
  - National Defense (Box 3)
  - Navy College Training Program (Box 3)
  - (Special) Nurses Training Program (Box 3)
  - Pre (Pre-Flight) Navy Cadets (Box 3)
  - Quartermaster Unit (Box 3)
  - Training of Tabulating Machine Supervisors (Box 3)
  - War Board (Box 3)
  - Wartime Commission (Box 3)
  - Wartime Commission Documents (Box 3)
  - Women Engineering Aids (Box 3)
- Financial records
  - General (Box 3)
  - Budget (to July 1, 1942) (Box 3)
  - Budget material 1941-1942, 2 folders (Box 3)
  - Budget (to July 1, 1943) (Box 3)
  - Budget material 1942-1943 (folders 1-2) (Box 3)
  - Budget material 1942-1943 (folder 3) (Box 4)
  - Budget (Faculty Personnel Committee), July 1943 (Box 4)
  - Budget (to July 1, 1944) (Box 4)
  - Budget material 1943-1944, 2 folders (Box 4)
  - Budget analysis 1943-1944 (Box 4)
  - Budget (to July 1, 1945) (Box 4)
  - Budget Administration Committee 1944-1945 (Box 4)
- Miscellaneous topical files
  - Teaching Fellow Study 1939-1942 (Box 4)
  - Four-Council Cooperative Higher Education Survey (Box 4)
  - Field notes 1941-1942 (Box 4)
  - University calendar (Box 4)
- Special Service Personnel
  - Report of survey (Box 4)
  - Employee lists (Box 4)
  - Form letters (Box 4)
  - Library budget (Box 4)
  - Titles 1943 (Box 4)
  - Allocation to ABC levels (Box 4)
  - Allocation lists 1941-1942 (Box 4)
  - Group allocations (Box 4)
  - Allocation announcement (clinical series) (Box 4)
  - Allocation announcement (counseling group) (Box 4)
  - Allocation announcement (research group) (Box 4)
  - Allocation announcement (curatorial group) (Box 4)
  - Allocation announcement (editorial group) (Box 4)
  - Allocation announcement (library) (Box 4)
  - Allocation announcement (nursing group) (Box 4)
  - Allocation announcement (social work) (Box 4)
  - Allocation announcement (technical series) (Box 4)
  - Allocation announcement (university relations series) (Box 4)